RG 074:044, Daughters of the American Revolution, Connecticut Chapters, Family Records
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Daughters of the American Revolution family records
1957-1998
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Daughters of the American Revolution
1.75 cubic feet
Genealogical records copied from different sources by members of DAR chapters in Connecticut.
RG074_044
Multiple
Scope and Content
Genealogical records copied from different sources by members of DAR chapters in Connecticut.
Related Material
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut Daughters of the American Revolution; Daughters of the American Revolution. Nathan Hale Memorial Chapter (East Haddam, Conn.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Orford Parish Chapter (Manchester, Conn.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Eunice Cobb Stocking Chapter (Glastonbury, Conn.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Faith Trumbull Chapter (Norwich, Conn.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Governor Jonathan Trumbull Chapter (Lebanon, Conn.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Green Woods Chapter (Winsted, Conn.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Hannah Woodruff Chapter (Southington, Conn.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Abigail Phelps Chapter (Simsbury, Conn.)
Document Types:
Genealogies
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
Accession 1979-042 received May 1979 from Connecticut DAR, Genealogical Records Committee, Mrs. Clifford P. Wicks, Jr. Additional material consisting of the Wilder Cemetery records received from Ms. Marilyn J. Pierce, Genealogical Records Chairman, Eunice Cobb Stocking Chapter, Glastonbury, on September 8, 1979. Accession 1997-001 received December 12, 1996 from Jean Bishop.
Container List
- Accession 1979-042, 1978-1979, undated
  - Eunice Cobb Stocking Chapter, Glastonbury
    - Pratt family records (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Copied from town record books in Shutesbury, Mass. Contains "Intentions to Marry," 1785-1871. Included is index indicating book and page where entries were found in original record books.
    - Cemetery records, Wilder Cemetery, Lancaster, New Hampshire. circa 1793-1940, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faith Trumbull Chapter, Norwich. Conn-Baptismal records performed by Rev. D.D. Lyons as recorded in his journal during the years 1843-87. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Governor Jonathan Trumbull Chapter, Lebanon. Genealogical material from the Maine Historical Magazine, Vol. 5, No. 7-9, Jan.-Mar. 1890, 1978 December 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Contains "Intentions of Marriage in Mount Desert, 1789-1809" and "Marriages at Deer Isle, 1832-1852."
  - Green Woods Chapter, Winsted (Box 1)
    - Bible record of Emma Tallmadge Bronson. circa 1737-1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Winsted United Methodist Church record. circa 1834-1892 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Copied from hand-written notebook.
  - Hannah Woodruff Chapter, Southington. Clark-Rule genealogy, Family record of Luke Guyant, Revolutionary soldier (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nathan Hale Memorial Chapter, East Haddam. Family records circa 1681-1856 from the Hartford Weekly Times, October 19, 1903. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Relating to Beers, Prindle, Hurd, Skidmore, Ferris, Bronson and Kinne families.
  - Orford Parish Chapter, Manchester. Records, circa 1010-1837, of the De Coigneries - Converse families. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Family records (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Accession 1997-001, 1957-1998, undated
  - Abigail Phelps Chapter, Simsbury
    - Bible records, Bagley Family, 1824-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bible of Edward Augustus Barber & Elizabeth Harris Watts (1848-1929) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bible records, Bidwell Family, Glastonbury, Connecticut, 1785-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bible records, Bradford and Johnson Families....1875-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Howard and Champlin Families, Connecticut, 1689-1847 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bible records of Crapo Family (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bible records, Curry Family, Hartford, Connecticut, 1843-1886 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bible records of the Davis Family, 1810-1906 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bible records, Damon Family, 1838-1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bible records, Dewey Family, Granby, Connecticut, 1816-1899 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bible records, Dunlap and Malcomson Familieis, Rushville, Illinois, 1834-1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bible records, Evans Family, 1858-1948, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bible records, Fox Family; Also, Fuller, Miner, Williams, Shumway; Hampton, Connecticut, 1759-1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bible records of Mrs. Barbara Carnwath Gardner (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bible records, Green Family, London, England, 1766-1802 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bible records, Harris, Waters, 1840-1963, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bible of George T. Hatherill & Addie Kerr Hatherill (1827-1961) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bible records, Henning Family, 1870-1915, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bible records, Johnson Family, Washington, D.C., 1871-1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bible records, Keene and Stanley Families, Palmyra, Hartland, and Pittsfield, Maine, 1855-1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bible records, Kelsey and Stevens Families, 1770-1935, Connecticut (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bible records, Kempton, Randolph, 1848-1968, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bible records, Murdock Family and black servant, Connecticut, 1740-1838 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bible records, Murdock Family, Connecticut, 1781-1866 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bible records, Newson, Michener, 1838-1966, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bible of Horace A. Nettleton, 1791-1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bible records of Janice M. Perkins of Simsbury, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bible records, Phelps Family, Andover, Connecticut, 1768-1921 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bible records of the Pratt Family, 1804-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bible records of Abner Reed, West Granby, CT, 1755-1832 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bible records, Robinson Family, Palmyra, Maine, 1842-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bible records, Roll Family, New Jersey, 1818-1932, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bible records of Russell Family, 1848-1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Town records, Harwinton, CT., Scoville Family, 1740-1891, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bible Records, Stancliff Family, Middletown and Portland, Connecticut, 1822-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bible records, Steele Family, Caldwell, New Jersey, 1760-1836 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bible records of the Wilson Family, 1789-1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bible records, Work Family, 1831-1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Old Union Center Cemetery, Cemetery Road near Old Union Library off 84 to Route 190 - Union, Connecticut, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Windsor Veterans Memorial Cemetery, Windsor, Connecticut, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Captain Noah Grant Chapter, Tolland (Box 1)
    - Bible records, Agard Family, 1815-1935, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Elkhorn Chapter (Wisc.) (Box 1)
    - Two Thompson ancestors 1637-1718 from England and Connecticut, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Eunice Cobb Stocking Chapter, Glastonbury (Box 1)
    - Family Bible records, Brooks Reig, 1818-1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bible records, Crow, Purple, 1830-1880, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Eve Lear Chapter, New Haven (Box 1)
    - Cemetery inscriptions, Granville, Vermont (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Formerly catalogued as 974.32 G767/Dld
  - Faith Trumbull Chapter, Norwich (Box 1)
    - Bible of Jehiel Berry given to his daughter Amy F. Berry on the occaision of her marriage to John C. Williamson in 1868, Dates 1740-1992, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bible records, Doty Family, 1844-1878, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bible records of Charles M. Eaton and Ruth Ann (Barnes) Eaton, Preston and NOrwich Connecticut, 1783-1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bible records, Finley family, 1824-1902, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bible records, Gardner Family, 1814-1881, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bible records of James and Zerviah Huntington and James Huntington 1809 and Benjamin Franklin Huntington 2nd from his mother 1893 Norwich, Connecitcut, 1783-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bible records, Stodder, Williams, Wheeler, 1742-1957, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Daughters of the American Revolution, Connecticut, Faith Trumbull Chapter, Norwich presents miscellaneous Bible records (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Formerly catalogued as 929.3 D265m
  - Governor Jonathan Trumbull Chapter (Box 1)
    - Research on the Hubbard Family, Connecticut, Vermont, 1601-1909, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hannah Benedict Chapter (Box 1)
    - Bible records, Austin, Barnhizer, 1801-1876, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Will of Peter Babb, 1820, Captain, Virginia militia, Frederick County, Virginia, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bible records, Griswold, Greswold, Bayles, 1788-1853, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mary Sillman Chapter (Box 1)
    - Bible records of Mrs. Frank Stevens Harrison of Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1854-1941, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Nathan Hale Memorial Chapter, East Haddam (Box 1)
    - Bible of Darius Bartlett and Betsy Stevens (1714-1828), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bible of George Wallace Bartlett (1871-1947), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bible of Amasa Tripp and Cordelia Hall Parker (1833-1941), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Orford Parish Chapter, Manchester (Box 2)
    - Bible of John A. Conklin & Clara A. Annible (1842-1982) and Sumner Family, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bible records, Converse Family, Ashford, Connecticut, 1770-1859; Watkins, Sessions, Converse, Tyler, Crawford, Jacobs, Mowry, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Family letters and records, Bolton, CT families, Section I; Lyman, Burdick, Chapman, Lull, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Putnam Hill Chapter, Greenwich (Box 2)
    - Research on the Sammis / Sandwayes Family, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sarah Whitman Hooker Chapter, West Hartford (Box 2)
    - Revolutionary soldiers buried in the Ancient Burying Ground (Old Cemetery), West Hartford, CT; Also, in the Quaker Meeting House Cemetery on South Quaker Lane, West Hartford, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Bible records, Atwood Family, Chatterson Family (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bible records, Attwood Family (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bible records, Jenkins Family (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Oath of fidelity, List of persons, 1777-1779-1771; Historical Society, West Suffied, Connecticut (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Connecticut DAR Genealogical Records Committee report, Series 2, Volume, Miscellaneous records, 1998; 1999-028 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Contents: A few inventors of Madison, CT; Some early Madison authors; Some pioneers of Ellington, CT; Death certificates of some Emmons relatives; Newspaper obituaries of Tolland County.
      This accession is in Box 2 Folder 5 of accession 1997-001.
    - Family and Bible records of Connecticut memebers of the Daughters of the American Revolution whose forebears came from several states, 1957 (Box 2)
      Formerly catalogued as 929.1 C76f 1957
    - Family and Bible records of Connecticut members of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1958 (Box 2)
      Formerly catalogued as 929.1 C76f 1958
    - Bible, family, cemetery and miscellaneous records from Connecticut chapters Daughters of the American revolution, 1959 (Box 2)
      Formerly catalogued as 929.1 C76f 1959
    - Family Bible records & history, circa 1968 (Box 2)
      Formerly catalogued as 929.1 C76f [1968]
- Accession: 1999-054, 1970-1977
  - Connecticut miscellany, Bible and family records, cemetery records, undertakers' records, wills, 1970 (Box 1)
    Formerly catalogued as 929.3 D265c 1970
  - Connecticut miscellany, 1971, Bible and family records, cemetery records, pastors' private journals (Box 1)
    Formerly catalogued as 929.3 D265c 1971
  - Connecticut miscellany, presented by Connecticut DAR chapters 1971-1973 (Box 1)
    Formerly catalogued as 929.3 D265c 1971/1973
  - Miscellaneous records, Fairfield, Hartford, New Haven, New London Counties, 1975 (Box 1)
    Formerly catalogued as 929.3 D265c 1975
  - Miscellaneous records, Fairfield, Hartford, New Haven, New London, and Tolland Counties, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    Formerly catalogued as 929.3 D265c 1975/76
  - Miscellaneous records, Fairfield, Hartford, New Haven, New London, and Tolland Counties, Connecticut, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
    Formerly catalogued as 929.3 D265c 1976/77